Clement Fung

Email: clement.y.fung@gmail.com
Website: https://clementfung.github.io/

SUMMARY

My current research interests include the security and privacy of distributed systems. Most notably, I am interested in distributed multi-party machine learning and corresponding attacks and defenses on these system. Lately, I am especially interested in the security and privacy issues surrounding Google's federated learning.

PUBLICATIONS

Non-refereed publications

- Muhammad Shayan, **Clement Fung**, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. Biscotti: A Ledger for Private and Secure Peer-to-Peer Machine Learning. arXiv November 2018.
- Clement Fung, Jamie Koerner, Stewart Grant, Ivan Beschastnikh.

 Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting.

 arXiv November 2018.
- Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. *Mitigating Sybils in Federated Learning Poisoning*. arXiv August 2018.

EDUCATION

MSc, Computer Science

2016 - 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Thesis:

• Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting. Supervisor: Ivan Beschastnikh

Achievements:

- UBC CS Department Graduate Teaching Assistant Award, 2017
- UBC CS Department Student Service Award, 2017

Research Projects:

- Biscotti: A secure, private blockchain-based system for multi-party machine learning
- FoolsGold: A sybil-resilient federated learning protocol against model poisoning
- TorMentor: A system for distributed, collaborative, anonymous machine learning
- InsuLearn: A system for distributed learning on private medical data
- DistributedClocks: A library for vector clock instrumentation of distributed systems

Graduate Courses:

• CPSC 532R - Graphical Models (*Prof. Siamak Ravanbakhsh*)

- CPSC 540 Advanced Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)
- CPSC 538W Data At Scale (*Prof. Andrew Warfield*)
- CPSC 538B Distributed Systems (*Prof. Ivan Beschastnikh*)
- CPSC 536F Algorithmic Game Theory (*Prof. Hu Fu*)
- CPSC 340 Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)

BASc, Honours Systems Design Engineering, Dean's Honour's List Distinction 2011 - 2016 University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Capstone Project:

• Driven: A Automated System for Intelligent Annotation and Analysis of Lane Change Sentiment Supervisor: Alexander Wong

Awards:

- Sanford Fleming Award for Co-operative Proficiency, 2016
- GM Canada Innovation Award, 2016 \$500
- W.W. King Exchange Fellowship, 2015 \$500
- President's International Experience Award, 2014 \$1500
- Sanford Fleming Award for Outstanding Communication in Work Term Report, 2013 \$300
- Colonel Hugh Heasley Engineering Scholarship, 2011 \$10000
- University of Waterloo President's Scholarship of Distinction, 2011 \$2000

Achievements:

- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2016
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2013 Ranked 2nd / 81 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Spring 2012 Ranked 2nd / 85 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Fall 2011 Ranked 3rd / 94 students

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

| Teaching Assistant University of British Columbia | Sept 2016 - Dec 2018 |
|---|----------------------|
| DSCI 571: Supervised Learning Instructors: Mikchael Gelbart, Varada Kolhatkar | Fall 2018 |

| • DSCI 523: Data Wrangling Instructors: Jenny Bryan, Rodolfo Lourenzutti | Fall 2018 |
|---|-------------|
| CPSC 340: Machine Learning Instructor: Michael Gelbart. | Winter 2018 |

| CPSC 340: Machine Learning | Fall 2017 |
|----------------------------|-----------|
| Instructor: Mark Schmidt | |

| Instructor: Mark Schmidt | |
|---|-------------|
| • CPSC 210: Software Construction | Winter 2017 |
| Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Paul Carter, Mehrdad Oveisi | |

• CPSC 210: Software Construction Fall 2016 Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Ryan Vogt, Jonatan Schroeder

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern

Oasis Labs, Berkeley, CA, USA

• Working on an early stage privacy-preserving blockchain

Software Engineering Intern

June - August 2015

January 2019 - present

LinkedIn Corporation, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

• Analytics: Building infrastructure for online relevance scoring at scale

Software Engineering Intern

September 2014 - December 2014

LinkedIn Corporation, Mountain View, CA, USA

• Distributed Data Systems: Prototyped and designed new derived data serving system, Venice

Software Engineering Intern

January 2014 - April 2014

Voicebox Technologies, Bellevue, WA, USA

• Server and Tools: Implemented layer for concurrent database access on a mobile service

Software Developer

May 2013 - August 2013

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research, Toronto, ON

• Software developer in Paul Boutros' bioinformatics research group

Software Developer

September 2012 - December 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON

QA Analyst

January 2012 - April 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON